[sirens wailing in distance]
Why is it taking so long
to get our system back online?
There'll be reasons.
Well. that's rather defeatist. isn't it?
We're supposed to be impregnable.
I have three questions.
How. why. what the living fuck is next?
And no answers.
Afraid heads are going to have to roll.
- [people chattering]
- Fuck.
[Diana]
Why is there a countdown?
It just appeared.
We don't know why. Not the best answer.
[Claude]
Well. it's not an answer.
[sighs]
Isn't there some kind of. uh. anti…
antivirus software
that you can use.
or maybe like a backdoor patch?
I don't think shouting out random words
you found at the bottom of emails
is going to help.
Thanks.
Um. okay. okay. Duncan.
What about… what about a reboot?
What. you mean turn it off and on again?
[chuckling] No.
Unless that would work. If we do that.
would that be any good at all?
You can't turn it off.
They can't do anything right now.
Claude. why don't we give them some space?
You should never have inputted
that code she gave you.
You should never have let her
leave the building.
I was only trying to
stop Libyan terrorists
from rampaging
through the fucking capital.
She wanted you to let her go.
What are you talking about?
She… She was terrified.
I had to convince her. I…
When Ho allowed her
to access the database.
she stole your file. Claude.
She played you. You've been profiled.
You've been honey-trapped.
[stammers]
[Roddy] You and me both. bro.
You didn't stand a chance.
She's a female me.
That's why I fell in love with her.
[Duncan]
Okay. um. good news. bad news.
There is a way to reverse
whatever they've done…
Great.
…but not before the countdown ends.
[chuckles] I'm so embarrassed for you.
[knocking on door]
- [agent] Sir.
- Yeah?
The Libyan ambassador's on line one.
In his own time.
I only made the call fucking hours ago.
Thank you.
[clears throat]
- Ambassador.
- Mr. Whelan. [breathing heavily]
My sincere apologies on behalf
of the Libyan government.
I have just been made aware that
a dissident group of security operatives
are responsible for the terrible events
of the last few days.
[Claude]
Yes. well. I'm sure that we can trust you
to do your very best to help us find them.
You can speak to one of them now.
Um. what. sorry?
This is the vulnerable young woman
you spoke to earlier.
Remember? You were right.
I am stronger than I thought.
with reserves of strength
I was not even aware of.
Who the hell are you really?
Someone who grew up in a country
ruined by your arrogant intervention.
You left us with years of horror.
Nothing can justify your slaughter
of 11 people.
I need to speak to someone in authority.
Guess what?
You're speaking to the head of MI5.
Yes. I know.
You kept telling me
when I was a trembling girl
you were trying to impress.
And since then.
we shut down your computer system
and humiliated your leadership.
Yeah. I guess we could say
we blinded our enemies.
Put Diana Taverner on.
Taverner.
Unless you give in to our demands.
when the countdown on your screen ends.
the final item
on the destabilization strategy…
you know. the one created by you
and inflicted on many of your colonies…
will be carried out.
What are your demands?
[Tara] £100 million.
Compensation for years
of lost oil revenues
to be paid into a Cayman Island trust
called Albion Holdings.
Which is a fraction of what we are owed.
Call me when you have it.
Relax. You'll get out when we're paid.
Bye.
They want 100 million
before that countdown ends.
or they will carry out
the remaining action on their list.
Uh. what's… what's the last action
on the list?
Attack a place of worship.
[Claude] Right.
But it's-it's Sunday morning.
Jesus fucking Christ.
How are we gonna find her?
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
["Strange Game" playing]
[phone buzzing]
[groans]
[sighs]
[grunts]
[buzzing continues]
[sighs deeply]
[sighs] Diana.
We lost Tara.
You knew she'd play Whelan. didn't you?
I had my suspicions.
Which were confirmed once I read his file.
His. uh. psych profile screams
"daddy savior complex."
Uh. I-I'd have given you a call.
but I thought you'd enjoy watching him
make a complete and utter
fucking tit of himself.
They issued any demands yet?
She just called from the embassy.
Free passage and 100 million
in lost oil revenue.
[scoffs]
Well. they might have a point
about our behavior.
but they trousered most of their oil money
and spent the change
keeping their people down.
They've crashed our systems
and given us an hour. which ends at 10:06.
Otherwise they attack a place of worship.
Oh. Sunday morning.
They've timed it well.
[grunts. sighs]
I guess you're just gonna have to
pay the money.
[line disconnects]
[Flyte] Ma'am.
There are around 2.000 churches
across London.
If you add in mosques. synagogues.
temples and multifaith centers.
we're looking at over 5.000
potential targets.
Yes. but. um.
Muslims don't worship on a Sunday.
I'm right in thinking that. aren't I?
Well. I'm… I'm Sikh.
Um. well.
let's assume it's churches. shall we?
High-value targets.
Uh. St. Paul's. Westminster Abbey.
[Diana]
They already have protection.
If we throw everything at St. Paul's.
and the attack happens elsewhere.
it'll look like we were rushing to protect
the landmarks rather than the people.
Okay. We shut 'em all down.
And how are we gonna get people
to stay away from every London church
in the next 40 minutes?
There'll be absolute chaos.
Call in the Met.
We don't have enough armed police.
Okay. then we call in the army.
[scoffs] In 40 minutes?
Ma'am. the Treasury have verified
the Cayman Island trust
where the money's to be paid.
It's linked to this company.
Jesus Christ. Right. Get him in.
- He's already on his way.
- [Diana] Keep him out of sight.
I'm sorry. why are we checking
where they want the money sent?
We're not gonna pay it.
I think we should have the option.
You need to call the PM now.
Get it cleared.
[scoffs] Give in to terror?
He won't hear of it.
Well. then. you are looking
at a second Abbotsfield.
Send the Dogs down to the Libyan embassy.
If this goes without bloodshed. we shall
escort her and her team to the airport.
If it goes the other way. I want them
to be ready to storm the building.
[River]
Shouldn't we be. you know. doing things.
like trying to track the Libyans
or-or-or Roddy's girlfriend?
Oh. she's at the Libyan embassy.
What. so it was a state-sanctioned op?
[grunts] No. I doubt that.
She forced her way in there
'cause she knows
- that we can't go in and drag her out.
- [phone buzzing]
[Jackson grunts]
That Grandpa?
No. Yes. How did you know that?
Well. if it was of operational relevance…
[sighs] …you would've taken it.
and you've got no personal life
so it must be him.
H-How's he doing. by the way?
Uh. not great. no.
He's picking up
on what's happening from the news.
but he's getting it slightly jumbled.
- Don't say anything.
- [sighs] About what?
About him getting confused. okay?
I know that you two had your differences.
but just leave it there.
He was the sharpest mind
in the building. After me.
Now you're gonna say something horrible.
Something unutterably vile about him
being an embarrassing shadow
of his former self.
I don't have to. You just said it for me.
- This isn't helping.
- I...
What are we going to do?
And don't say. "nothing."
[chuckles] There's nothing to do.
These guys are bloody good
and they're fucking ruthless.
The Park can't protect
every church in London.
Well. then they will have
to pay the money.
- [River] And what happens if they don't?
- Then there'd be a massacre.
At a random church in London?
- This is a nightmare.
- [Jackson] Maybe not that random.
There is one place of worship
I can think of.
Although. it would only occur to
a complete and utter fucking psychopath.
You think he knows which one?
Shit.
Wait. w-where are they going?
Abbotsfield.
Abbotsfi… There's already been
an attack at Abbotsfield.
Which they are commemorating
at a multifaith center shortly.
You can't just say shit like that
and then just sit there and do nothing.
I'm not doing nothing.
I'm sending my best agents.
And you.
May I ask why I've been summoned here
then made to wait on the stairs
like a member of staff?
When you came to visit me the other night.
you mentioned a group of
disaffected Libyans wanting compensation
for lost oil revenues.
As of now. we have 25 minutes
to pay up 100 million
to stop a Libyan group
from attacking a church.
I have no knowledge of any of this.
It's an extremely fractured country.
and in my limited experience.
every fucker you meet is on the take.
The people you're dealing with may be
part of a completely separate group.
The payment has to go to an offshore trust
where you are a director.
In that case. fuck. shit. bugger and yes.
it seems it is the same people.
I will never do business
in the Middle East again.
They love to haggle.
and they have a tendency
to go completely fucking crackers.
Why do they have your details?
There are two accounts.
One to distribute funds to them
once they've come in. minus my commission.
Nothing in that one at the moment.
obviously.
- And the other?
- [inhales deeply]
They've paid me a nominal fee
for the last three years.
Recently they intimated
I wasn't doing enough.
- hence my visit to you.
- And when you say "nominal." you mean…
All told. a couple of hundred grand.
Which I will declare in due course.
Why are they dragging me
into this insanity?
It makes me look terrible.
Because you took their money
and did nothing and they want to show
what a corrupt mess this country is.
Getting paid through
the former Home Secretary
is a very good way of doing it.
When this comes out.
we will all look terrible.
[Claude] Prime Minister.
I'm afraid it's highly unlikely the attack
can be prevented without paying.
No. No. I'm as disappointed as you are.
Um… [stammers]
[sighs]
Twelve minutes. sir.
Well. Taverner's left us with no choice.
Mmm.
They didn't give us an hour
to stop the killing.
They gave us an hour to find the money.
We have been outplayed.
[access panel screeches]
[line ringing]
[phone rings]
We will pay. But I want your word
the attack will be called off.
And I want your word
we'll be allowed to leave the country.
[Diana] Cars will be arriving shortly.
ready to take you to RAF Northolt.
But safe passage is only guaranteed
if you and all your team leave
to ensure there is no further violence.
Oh. and also. none of this ever comes out.
I can imagine
you must feel humiliated. huh?
Unpleasant. isn't it?
Do you agree to our terms?
I'll stand them down. and they will
return to the embassy shortly.
Any more violence.
and those men in the cars
will not be taking you to the airport.
They will be taking you down.
There'll be no more violence.
Transfer authorized.
So I see.
[sighs]
[phone buzzes]
[Tara. in Arabic] They paid. We did it.
Get back to the embassy.
They're going to fly us out of here.
You're starting to believe your role.
You're a recruit.
Not the one who gives orders.
What are you talking about?
It's over.
Not for us.
[Tara] Listen.
If you do anything else.
they're going to storm the building.
[line disconnects]
[phone clatters]
Get ready.
Did they pay?
So?
Why should that stop us?
And this?
What about this? Huh?
I want them to pay in blood.
like the blood I saw spilled.
They smashed our country
then went back to their lives.
leaving us with the horror of war.
They must feel the same horror.
Maybe next time they will think twice
before they start a war and walk away.
[breathing heavily]
- Where the fuck are you going?
- Look.
You pick your target.
and I will pick mine.
Guys. enough innocents have died.
The last blow should fall on the people
that caused the war.
I'm only going to spill the blood
of the guilty.
As justice for my family.
What about you?
Come on. bro.
[sighs]
[in English] Don't know how you can eat
at a time like this.
[sighs]
Is that vegan?
No. I asked for meat.
Yeah. but if that was meat.
it would be bright pink.
[sighs]
Sausage rolls got a…
Yes. all right.
If you were coming out of that building.
trying to lose the Dogs…
[inhales deeply]
…which direction would you head?
Do you think Tara's going
to try and escape?
- Answer the question.
- Um…
Uh. left. Left down that alley.
You said that they'll all get free passage
out of the country
if she calls off this attack.
Well. she's just a kid.
There's no way she's running the show.
Yes. her men should've been
back here by now.
I don't think they're coming back.
I think she's sitting in there
realizing she never was in control
of her band of psychos.
But you said we're paying the money.
Well. look at what these guys have
got up to in the last couple of days.
And I don't think money is gonna
quell their rage.
[car doors opening. closing]
[Jackson] Now Dogs are going in.
But innocent people could get caught
in the cross fire.
Yeah. they're in more danger
from our trigger-happy muscle
than they are from her.
We can't just sit here.
- Well. go on then.
- What?
Go and knock on the door.
What? Me?
Yesterday. you physically assaulted
the mayor.
I don't know why you're
getting your knickers in a twist
about knocking on a door.
- Yesterday. I had no choice.
- Oh. bollocks.
You get a real thrill
from being in the action.
Probably it reminds you
of the rush you used to get
when you got absolutely arseholed.
[sighs]
Well. what am I doing
after I knock on the door?
Telling her to follow you.
Unless she wants to get shot in the head.
[stammers] They're not gonna shoot her
out here. unarmed in the street.
It's a different story
if they go in the building.
And like you said.
- innocent people could get hurt.
- Guess I did say that. didn't I?
[Jackson] That's it. They won't look twice
at a harmless little old lady.
Cool.
[sighs]
[mouthing] Knock. knock. knock.
[Dog] Uh. sorry. ma'am. Embassy's closed.
No. it's all right. I have an appointment.
- Ma'am. you are not allowed to be here.
- [Tara] Who are you?
Yes. I'm MI5. let me in.
Step back from the building. please.
Let me in nicely or men
with guns are coming in.
Okay. ma'am. I'm gonna have to remove you.
- [door beeps]
- [sighs]
[Dog sighs]
- [pants]
- [rapid beeping]
So. how exactly can you help?
You'll be perfectly safe if you put down
that weapon and come with me now.
Why should I believe you?
You don't have much choice.
because if you stay in here armed.
you could get hurt.
[gasps]
Open the door then. Go. open.
Update your hostage list.
Someone else just walked in.
- [Dog 2] Eyes up!
- [Tara] Back off!
- No?
- [Dog 2] Down!
- Put the gun down!
- You could have just walked out with me.
- [Dog 3] Put the gun down!
- And what? Back into the Park. huh?
Why would I want that?
[Dog 1] Put the gun down!
I told you to back off!
- [Dog 2] Stop moving!
- They'll kill you.
- [Dog 1] Put the gun down! Now!
- I'm gonna shoot!
I'm not fucking joking. I'll shoot!
[Dog 1] Put the gun down!
[grunts]
- [gunshot]
- [Catherine yelps]
- [Dog 1 shouts]
- [gunfire]
[panting]
[panting continues]
Déjà vu.
Come. hands up. Up. on your head.
[grunting]
Oh. come on. Cheer up.
I'd take prison any day
over dating Roddy Ho.
Fuck you! [breathing heavily]
[Dog 1] Lima. golf 5-7 to control.
We've apprehended the suspect.
We're bringing her in now. Over.
[sighs]
You knew that was going to happen.
didn't you?
Yeah.
And like I said. she's just a kid.
She was never gonna shoot ya.
Well. it didn't feel like that. [panting]
Come on.
- I'll buy you a lemonade.
- [sighs] Oh.
Take the edge off.
[in Arabic]
More will die than in the first attack.
All of them will die.
[in English] The hour's nearly up.
We need to get them out of there.
Yeah. but calmly. We don't want panic.
They might already be inside
dressed as mourners.
It's what I'd do.
I still don't have a gun.
Don't worry. We've still got ours.
Oh. how'd that work out for Gimball?
[mourners]
♪ Till we have built Jerusalem ♪
♪ In England's green and pleasant land ♪
William Blake wrote those words
of promise over 200 years ago.
but they continue to inspire
and comfort today.
But for more contemporary wisdom
that might give solace
to our younger mourners.
I reach for the words
of Dominic Toretto in Furious 7.
"They say to live in the hearts
of those we leave behind is not to die."
The lesson I take from both those sages.
separated though they are by centuries.
is that while London might not
be "Londerful" today.
it will be "Londerful" tomorrow
if we channel...
Yeah. right. Everyone. up.
We need you to leave this building
as quickly as possible. please.
- What's going on?
- Sorry. we're MI5. I don't have…
- Can you show them your… the badge?
- Stand back.
Yeah. maybe you should've started
with taking them aside.
Everyone. intelligence has come to light
that means it's best for you
to leave right now.
So please do so
from the back of the building.
No need to panic. everyone.
Just slowly. safely exit the building.
[River] Everyone. now please! Come on!
I mean it. now! Get out!
Everyone. come on. now! Please!
[alarm blaring]
What the fuck happened to "calmly"?
Hang on. What the hell is going on?
I'd only just started my eulogy.
Apologies. sir. I know. but we need to
get you to leave the building now.
- Whoa. whoa. All right.
- Hang on. Is it a fire?
- No. there's not a fire.
- Then why did he hit the alarm?
- Yeah. good question.
- [River] It's a security threat. okay?
- A security threat has come to light.
- What kind of threat?
Libyan operatives are extorting
the government for £100 million.
I can't hear you.
Sorry. Can someone turn
that fucking thing off. please?
[alarm continues. muffled]
[people clamoring]
In under a minute.
we have to pay £100 million
or a place of worship
is gonna be attacked.
and we have reason to believe
it could be here. Please. just believe…
- [alarm stops]
- Oh. thank God. Did you get that?
Yes. You have reason to believe
this place could be attacked.
- Yeah. so please. let's leave now.
- But you don't know for sure?
Intelligence is never 100% certain. sir.
[Zafar] What percentage would you put
on this piece of intelligence?
- That really matter?
- Yes. I'm the Mayor of London.
If an attack was highly likely.
- I should've been informed.
- Well…
[River] Fuck. Not now.
[chattering]
Look. it really is not the time
to argue about protocol.
- Get Whelan on the line.
- Seriously. I need him to leave now.
[in Arabic] We can get them outside.
The mayor is still here.
I was cheated out of killing him before.
- We get him first.
- Okay.
[speaks Arabic]
- You distract his security team.
- [grunts]
- [in English] What's your name?
- My…
- Uh. River Cartwright.
- River?
Yes.
Claude. I'm here with River Cartwright.
who's crashed into the memorial service
babbling something about a Libyan attack
that none of my agents
seem to know anything about.
Right.
Um. well. first of all. uh.
apologies on that. Zafar. Apologies.
Um… [clears throat]
…uh. y-y-you should have been
kept in the loop on that.
although in our defense.
it has been a very fast-moving situation.
[clamoring]
- [mouthing] Yes.
- [Zafar] Was there gonna be an attack
on the service or not?
- Yes. yes. there was.
- Shush.
To be honest.
we had no intelligence either way
that you were specifically under threat.
Of course. if-if we had received
that information. then… then…
- then we would've intervened.
- Now hang on.
you did intervene. I'm stood in front
of a load of your agents.
[Claude] Would you mind putting
Cartwright on for me. please?
[breathing shakily]
Wants to speak to you.
- Sir.
- What the fuck are you doing?
We thought the attack was
gonna be at Abbotsfield.
[Claude] Yeah. well.
we paid them the money.
There's not gonna be an attack anywhere.
And certainly not at Abbotsfield.
- [glass shatters]
- [person exclaims]
[gunfire]
Get out!
[grunts]
[groans]
[gunfire on phone]
[panting] Have you actually
used one of those?
[stammers] You had the better angle.
Are you okay?
[River] Fuck.
- [groans]
- Shit.
[piano strings ringing]
- How many have you got left?
- Enough.
[Zafar panting. whimpering]
Shit.
Just give him what he wants.
For fuck's sake. give him what he wants.
I want to get out of the country.
- The deal still stands.
- [Zafar] What deal?
With MI5. Safe passage.
Oh. you're kidding. right?
You're not getting safe passage.
You broke that deal when you opened fire.
- Don't say that to him.
- Well. I'm not gonna lie.
I'd really rather you lied.
Let me out of here or I shoot your mayor!
- No. not happening.
- Yes. otherwise he'll shoot him.
Do not aim for his neck.
We've established you're a shit shot.
There's other parts of him to aim for.
I'm going to walk out of here
and I'm taking him with me.
- No. we can't let you do that.
- Yes. you can.
Can you stop fucking contradicting me?
Yeah. I will if you stop escalating
a dangerous situation.
- I'm on top of it. I know what I'm doing.
- We've got a madman
pointing a gun at a hostage.
I say let him do what he wants.
You see. that's why you're never gonna
get out of Slough House.
[shouts]
[strains]
[gasps] Oh. shit. Shit.
Where… Where did you come from?
I approached him very. very quietly.
[Zafar panting]
You two… You two staged your argument
to give him cover.
I get that. I get that. I get that now.
[panting] Fuck. [sighs]
- Yeah. yeah.
- [Zafar groans]
It's unorthodox. yeah.
But. uh. you just gotta. um.
think outside the box sometimes.
[smacks lips] Don't you?
[panting] Yeah.
[Flyte] We have accounted
for all the Libyans.
Two were shot at Abbotsfield.
and Lamb apprehended Tara.
What was he doing there?
- I don't know. ma'am.
- [sighs]
[sighs]
We pay up and they attack anyway.
What a shit show.
You didn't have a choice.
When they pick over the bones of this.
you'll be exonerated. ma'am.
[scoffs]
London rules will kick in.
[Flyte] London rules?
[Diana] If you were Service.
you'd know that.
Moscow rules. watch your back.
London rules. cover your arse.
[phone buzzing]
[buzzing continues]
[sighs]
Claude Whelan. Peter Judd.
It seems both of us have
a public relations problem
vis-à-vis our connection
to events of the last week.
Might I propose
a solution of mutual benefit?
Hiya. It's me. It's River.
[chuckling] Oh. my boy.
- You all right?
- Oh. you're here.
- Yeah.
- [chuckling] Ah.
Oh. [breathes heavily]
Oh. I'm so happy.
Me too. Yeah.
[stammering] I'm sorry
about that phone call. Last night.
[stammering] I don't think
I was making much sense.
- It's fine.
- Probably no help to you.
It's fine. It's fine.
Who was it?
The Russkies up to their old tricks?
No. um…
It was Libya.
- [sighs. murmuring] Libya.
- [bees buzzing]
It was chaos.
Yeah.
I think
that's what they wanted to instill.
As a way of ransoming us.
And it worked because…
Well. we… we paid them the money
but they. uh. attacked anyway.
- [chuckles]
- [buzzing continues]
It looks like absolute chaos.
but if you follow them
you can see there's a method.
- Yeah.
- I like to follow them individually.
Libyans?
What?
Bees.
Buzzy. buzzy bees.
Strong work ethic. bees.
[clicks tongue]
Sting in the tail.
That's what I was trying
to remember last night.
[grunts] I'm losing my mind.
- The unwritten rule.
- [clicks tongue] What's that?
Destabilization.
Yes. you see. if ever we were dealing
with some really tricky buggers. we…
we'd hit them
when they thought it was over.
That's what we call a sting in the tail.
- Let them know who's boss.
- Yeah.
Well. that's why
they attacked anyway. Yeah.
[chuckles]
We weren't always at our best. River.
You know?
But some of those colonies would've
turned red. left to their own devices.
- Still. you caught them all.
- [intriguing music plays]
Oh. I'm so happy you came.
You must tell me
what you want for your birthday.
I know it's a way off.
but I… I can't go to the shops.
and I can't work
that computer you gave me.
I'd give you money
if I could get to the bank.
Just have to make a call.
Yeah. o-of course.
[suspenseful music plays]
There's gonna be a sting in the tail.
Well. they did that when
they attacked the multifaith center.
[sighs] So unless you're telling me
they are now fucking zombies.
I don't see the point of this call.
Shirley has a picture of three pairs
of boots in the back of that van.
but that's four men
including the driver. right?
You and Shirley got one
of them after Roddy's.
and we got two of them at Abbotsfield.
So that means there's one left.
- Lamb?
- [stammers] Yeah. I'm here.
Well. part of her dating Ho
was to get a file.
[breathes deeply] I read it.
Who do you think deserves a punishment
greater than utter humiliation?
["Fall At Your Feet" plays on earphones]
[panting] That was pretty good.
[sighs]
Yeah. shook the dust off.
Got rid of today's stress.
[exhales sharply] And you know
what I'm gonna do tonight?
I'll bloody well treat myself.
Crack open a nice bottle of Chalk Hills.
You got any plans. Jim?
[tense music plays]
Jim?
Jim. are you…
Oh. fuck.
Oh. fuck. Fuck.
[tense music swells]
Fuck.
[breathing heavily]
Sorry. Jim.
[brakes screech]
[doorbell ringing]
[softly] Come on. come on.
[mutters]
[exclaims] What?
Where are the keys?
Where are the fucking keys?
[engine revs]
This is Claude Whelan.
Who? First Desk.
- I'm the First Desk. you moron.
- Throw it!
Do you know who I am?
Uh…
- No.
- I'm someone who suffered.
Because of a keystroke you made.
[scoffs] I literally have no idea
what the hell you're talking about. I...
Zlitan. 2011.
Right. Yeah.
You left us to gangsters and militias.
and you did not arm us against them.
Listen. I… I was just paid
to give opinions. is all. That's...
Your opinion as a long-term forecaster
was that an investment in Libya
was poor value.
Because whether it stood or fell.
it did not affect the security
of the United Kingdom.
Your opinion…
[breathing shakily]
Your opinion became policy.
How's that opinion looking now?
Not great.
Listen to me.
You're obviously upset.
But I'm…
[inhales sharply] I'm…
[breathing heavily] Please.
Just think of my…
- think of my wife. please.
- I am.
She can feel what I did.
- At least she'll have a body to bury.
- [dog walker] Come back. Pip!
- I never found my father.
- [dog barking]
[dog walker] Come on. Pip.
- [barking continues]
- [tense music swells]
[dog walker] Sorry about that.
He's very friendly…
Oh. my God!
[barking continues]
Fuck.
[panting]
[grunting]
[gunshots]
[panting]
- [breathing heavily]
- Is he dead?
Yes. I can do my job.
Thank fuck for that.
[River] Fuck.
A good job.
[breathing heavily]
How'd you find me?
I went to your house and your wife
said you'd be running around here.
- You met my wife?
- Yeah.
Yeah. and what'd she say?
- That you'd be running around here.
- Yeah.
Yeah. Listen. thank you. Thank you.
Yep.
Actually. come here. Thank you.
Thank you. thank you so. so much.
I won't forget this.
You know. I'm just. um…
I really need a drink.
[bell rings]
[news reporter] More details have emerged
about the shooting yesterday
on Primrose Hill.
Whilst police have not released
the identity of the gunman.
the incident is not believed
to be drug-related.
He's waiting in your office.
[clears throat. sighs]
That's why I'm in here.
He's First Desk. Lamb.
And this is a big win for Slough House.
You wanna piss him off
and throw that away?
You giving me career advice?
I've actually done the job you play at.
I'm just saying.
I did save his life.
- So?
- So it's an opportunity.
- For who?
- Everyone.
You think you're going back to the Park.
don't you?
Aw. bless.
You don't want me here.
and I don't wanna be here.
Suits us both.
You can leave anytime you want.
That's the whole point of Slough House.
Not sure how you missed that.
I'm not leaving the Service.
But I shouldn't be in Slough House.
'Cause I'm really fucking good.
And you know that.
[sniffles]
You know. it's not the hope
that kills you. Cartwright.
It's knowing it's the hope
that kills you. that kills you.
[grunts]
Beppe. he'll get this.
So I'll get the bill and you'll ask him?
[sniffles. sighs]
[sighs]
If it comes up.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[sighs]
This is Louisa. Leave a message.
[phone beeps]
Hey. It's. uh… It's me.
Um…
[smacks lips] I know I'm supposed to be
giving you space or whatever. but. uh…
Well. I actually don't have
anyone else to call.
'Cause it's. um… [clicks tongue]
Well. it looks like
I'm leaving Slough House too.
[footsteps approaching]
[Jackson breathing heavily]
Hello. Didn't know you were here.
- Yes. you did.
- [panting] Yes. I did.
We gotta get that fucking lift mended.
[exhales heavily]
- [Claude] You enjoying this. are you?
- Eh. not particularly.
Oh. but go on. Do your bit.
[grunts] I imagine you worked it all out.
You practice in front of the mirror.
or do you find it hard
to look yourself in the eye?
Sc… Do you mind? Could you not…
Could you not do that here. please?
This is MI5 property. after all.
- [ashtray clatters]
- Fuck MI5. My gaff. my rules.
Yeah. about that.
Um…
Not anymore. I'm afraid.
- [sighs] Oh. really?
- Mmm.
Your gaff. as you term it. is no more.
[chuckles] Thing of the past. Literally.
One understands that you've been allowed
to run this place under sufferance
because of. uh…
Well. because of what
you've done for the Service.
But you know. there are lines.
That there are limits.
Two of us know you're way over both.
You do remember yesterday. right?
When one of my team
saved your life. [chuckling]
I… [chuckles] …I'm beginning
to regret giving him the tip-off.
- Yes. My life was only in danger because…
- Also...
- …another member of your delinquent te...
- Also in the ledger of things
that Slough House has not fucked up.
which. I grant you.
is a little thin in the grand scheme.
is that I caught the femme fatale
behind this week's
fucking bloodshed and chaos
without your goons
having a firefight in an embassy.
But I suppose that's why. yeah?
Yeah. y-you wanna bury the fact that she…
she batted her eyelids
and you let her walk out of the building
and fuck up the MI5 mainframe
all at the same time.
[smacks lips] You know. it's funny. I. um…
I have a totally different narrative.
Yeah. I'm sure you do.
Yeah. let me guess.
Judd gets to keep the commission on
the hundred mil for saying that. um. he…
he tried to warn me about
the Libyans and Tara's connection to Ho
and I did nothing.
Yeah. you blame it all on Slough House.
and you get to keep your job.
Yeah?
Checkmate. mate.
[chuckles]
Yeah. well. it looks like I'm fucked.
You know. I don't like to use that word.
but yes. You're fucked.
You're all totally fucked.
Fucked. [chuckles] Apart from Cartwright.
because he shows some promise. I feel.
- and deserves a second chance.
- Oh. he'll only balls it up.
Right. Well. I'll see myself out. shall I?
[chuckles] Oh. by the way.
Um. there's a… there's a team
coming by later today to. uh…
Clean this place up.
[sighs] You'll leave quite a stain.
But it'll be gone.
[Claude on Dictaphone] Now.
anymore crap from either of you two
and I will see to it
the security services destroys you
and your god-awful livelihoods in public.
I'm sorry. what was that?
What was what?
- That… [stammers] I overheard. um…
- Oh. that.
Uh… Yeah.
That was you
threatening a political figure
hours before he was killed.
I'll play you the other bits if you like.
where his wife talks about
your sugar daddy behavior and…
and you blackmail him
about his Turkish dad.
In case it slipped your mind.
I mean. it might have done.
You've had a busy week.
You know what. I was. um…
I was probably a tad premature. wasn't I?
- [scoffs]
- [stammering] When I said "checkmate."
it was more like "check." wasn't it?
You know. so I… I do a move. and you do…
[stammering] What do you want?
I want what I always want.
To be left in utter fucking peace.
[breathes deeply] All right.
All right.
Slough House stays.
So does Molly Doran.
I love Molly. Molly's a lot of fun.
- Uh. that was never my decision.
- And Ho comes back.
Ho? The man's an utter fucking liability.
- Absolutely not.
- Ho comes back.
He's the only one
who can manage my Deliveroo account.
[sighs]
[chuckles]
Fine. If he. uh… Right. okay. O… Okay.
So then. uh… [chuckles]
…who do you propose that we hang this on?
Well. we pin it on the. uh…
on the fucking chump who deserves to go.
- You.
- [scoffs] Me? [chuckles]
No. No. No way. No.
No. no. no. no.
I'm. um… I'm not going anywhere.
[Gimball on Dictaphone]
But you still paid a call girl.
who. incidentally. you were also boffing.
If you're not out of your office
within the hour.
I'm gonna send this to every grubby
little hack I know from my drinking days.
That's going to do untold damage
toward the Service and you know that.
Like I give a fuck.
Look what the Service has done to me.
Yeah. and leave the door open
on your way out.
I like a through draft.
I'm sure we'll meet again.
[sighs] I doubt that.
I don't use prostitutes.
- She wasn't a prostitute.
- [urinating]
She wasn't. that was…
She wasn't… Oh. fuck.
I… I don't know
where everybody gets this from.
She wa… That was. um…
She was an escort.
Roddy Ho is on his way back to you.
I am not taking Cartwright.
Yeah. it's fine.
I'm a little short on numbers anyway.
You wanna keep him?
[grunts] You never know.
Might need a… a new liver.
Anyway. it was. uh. me that worked out
Whelan was the target...
Don't tell me you want
to come back to the Park.
Oh. fuck off.
Well. nice as it is to chat.
I'm in the middle of moving offices. So…
Well. I hope that now you're First Desk
you won't forget the little people.
Door's always open for a coffee
and a catch up. [chuckles softly]
Do I detect a note of sarcasm?
Absolutely.
I never wanna hear from you
or anyone else at the Park again.
An arrangement that suits
both of us. Jackson.
[sighs]
- [knocks on door]
- Would you just fuck off?
Oh. it's nice to see you too.
[intense. dramatic music plays]
His dad stole a file…
- [grunts]
- …with the Slow Horses' names in it.
Now he's dead
and my joes are being hunted.
Slough House is completely missing.
We don't exist anymore.
You got a leak Julian Assange
would be proud of.
- Our security…
- [groans]
[grunts]
…in these hands.
- We're running out of time.
- What?
- [Jackson] It's a bloodbath.
- [gasps]
[all clamoring]
[grunts]
- If you're in trouble…
- How dare you?
- I'm the sort of person…
- Fuck do you think you are?
…who would fuck up someone's day.
[River] What are you doing here?
Business.
[tires squealing]
- [grunts]
- No one is unaccountable. Diana.
No one.
We need to address the five Fs.
Who the fuck. what the fuck.
where the fuck and why the fuck?
[grunts]
That's four.
[sighs] Fuck off. That's five.
Well. go on then. Fuck off.
["Strange Game" playing]
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-